Rise together or fall alone.
Godzilla x Kong: The New Empire is a action, adventure,
science fiction film directed by Adam Wingard.
Following their explosive showdown, Godzilla and Kong must reunite against a colossal undiscovered
threat hidden within our world, challenging their very existence – and our own.
Ilene Andrews, played by Rebecca Hall.
Bernie Hayes, played by Brian Tyree Henry.
Trapper, played by Dan Stevens.
Jia, played by Kaylee Hottle.
Mikael, played by Alex Ferns.
Iwi Queen, played by Fala Chen.
Godzilla x Kong: The New Empire is a 2024 American monster
film directed and co-written by Adam Wingard.
Produced by Legendary Pictures and distributed by Warner Bros.
Pictures, it is the sequel to Godzilla vs.
Kong (2021), the fifth Godzilla film to be completely produced by a Hollywood studio, and the fifth film in the
Monsterverse franchise, also serving as the 38th film of the Godzilla franchise and 13th in the King Kong franchise.
The film stars Rebecca Hall, Brian Tyree Henry, Dan Stevens,
Kaylee Hottle, Alex Ferns, and Fala Chen.
Hall, Henry, and Hottle reprise their roles from the previous film.
In the film, Kong encounters more of his species in the Hollow Earth and must unite again with Godzilla to stop
the tyrannical Skar King and the powerful, frost-breathing Shimo from invading the Earth's surface.
Following the box office and streaming success of Godzilla vs.
Kong during the COVID-19 pandemic, Legendary announced a sequel in March
2022 and that filming would commence later that year.
In May 2022, it was announced that Wingard would return to
direct and Stevens had been cast as a lead.
Filming began in July 2022 in Gold Coast,
Australia, and finished in November 2022.
Godzilla x Kong: The New Empire premiered at Grauman's Chinese Theatre on March
25, 2024, and was released in the United States on March 29.
The film received mixed reviews from critics, with many comparing it unfavorably
to Godzilla Minus One, which had been released four months prior.
It grossed $572.5 million worldwide against a production budget of $135–150 million, becoming the eighth-highest-grossing film
of 2024 and the highest-grossing film of the Monsterverse, as well as in the Godzilla and King Kong franchises.
A sequel, Godzilla x Kong: Supernova, is slated for March 26, 2027.
The film explores themes of giant monster, sequel, dinosaur, monkey, kaiju.
The tone is thought_provoking.